foreign
let's just say this isn't your typical
Airbnb
[Music]
hello how are you doing thank you for
having us happy hosting Sophie Sophie
she'll be co-hosting with us today she's
such a good host
and this is your house it's my house
[Music]
I love it yeah here we are this is
the infamous Airbnb of all airbnbs this
is this is where it all happens I love
your coffee table book game I'm like
really into coffee oh yeah it's cool
right yours are pretty good there's a
lot of like cool design books here
um and like a lot of memorabilia like
there's a Obama owes this is literally
how we funded the company we sold
collectible breakfast cereal and you
became serial entrepreneurs yes you'll
see that one's autographed by the actual
president Obama and you hand made these
right we hand made these we designed
these with a team and I literally hot
glued this one myself
Joe made me this one this is my IPO gift
this would be my kids favorite jeske's
charm Jessica's charms see if Jessica's
chips chesky's charms
I love this house it's beautiful
honestly it's a nice balance because you
know I live alone I don't want to like a
you know weird Technic Mansion you know
it's super modern I'm not gonna name
names but you know people my age buying
100 million dollar homes yeah yeah not
my thing
what's it been like playing hosts so far
oh my God it's been it's been a lot of
fun um uh I'm a co-host I got Sophie
Supernova she's uh nearly one Euro a
two-year-old golden retriever it's been
cool because I haven't really hosted
that much since the early days you're
kind of busy you're running a
multi-billion dollar company like what
made you want to make time for this I
never wanted to be one of those CEOs
that's kind of an ivory Tower just
looking at data and spreadsheets all day
when you first build a company you make
something usually for yourself people
aren't just numbers they're people and
that means that you need to be
emotionally connected to what you're
doing I understand what hosts are
complaining about something or your
customers complaining what do they mean
so that's like the main reason I did it
but then there was another reason I
wasn't expecting which was this fun it
was crazy to think you were going to
rent your house to a stranger or that
you were going to stay in some
stranger's house and now it's just what
we do yeah does the level of human
openness to that idea still surprise you
I think I'm less a Visionary than
expeditionary in the sense that I didn't
have a vision I discovered something one
week and I couldn't pay rent I decided
to let people in my house only to make
money for the most part I thought it'd
be fun and I ended up becoming friends
these people
but it made me realize that like these
homes are these private spaces that you
you'd never let anyone in but you
understand why there's no trust and we
thought well if we could solve a system
of trust and make them not feel like
strangers this would be an idea that
spread on the world I think we have
trouble imagining sociological changes
sometimes harder than technological
changes we can all imagine things
getting bigger faster but it's hard to
imagine us changing Behavior but Airbnb
has actually been a big part of like
maybe a major sociological change
probably I mean it's been now
been used 1.4 billion times and if you
had told me
when we first started that 1.4 billion
people
from 220 countries and regions will live
together
that on a typical night we'd have nearly
the population of Los Angeles staying
together people from the Middle East and
Texas like cultures you wouldn't
necessarily think mixing together I
think we all would have said you were
crazy it's like most tech companies have
to understand laws of physics we call
these first principles and we also have
to know a different law which is a law
of human nature like who are we at a
very basic level and if you can start to
understand that then you can start to
design for people you know obviously the
pandemic hit travel comes to a
screeching call the majority of your
Revenue almost vanishes also nobody
wants to see other people right
in that moment did it feel like you were
standing on the edge of a cliff I
thought we had made it before the
pandemic you know we had a business that
was doing like let's call it 35 billion
dollars in sales that's more than
Starbucks that's almost like the size of
Nike if you told me in like the 1980s
growing up we'd have a business that
baby you're totally crazy I thought
we're making working IPO if they don't
lose 80 percent of it in eight weeks I
mean you remember there were articles
like is this the end of Airbnb will
Airbnb exist
I gotta tell you like that changed my
life
and it changed my life and the company
for the better how you ever hear people
say that they had a near-death
experience and they had this Moment of
clarity well thankful I've never had
that but I felt like I got that Clarity
from the business perspective how did
you change as a person
we'll see my hair is a little greater
but um I think I really grew up during
the pandemic I think I felt my
responsibility more employees were
worried about their jobs investors worry
about their investment guests were
worried about they can get their money
back when they're traveling and they
were all reaching out to me at the same
time and not in a low-key composed way
and I remember my board member Ken
Chenault who's a CEO of Amex
he was CEO during 9 11 in the financial
crisis 2008 and he basically said I've
been through two of the biggest crises
my lifetime and this is 10 times bigger
than either of them he said this is your
defining moment as a CEO and I think I
had lessons that have now been seared in
my brain and I'm never going to forget
that what are the lessons so the first
thing I learned is who people really are
the good news is that the vast majority
of people turned out to be great people
I learned to focus the entire company
and point them every single person to
One Direction and I learned to stop
apologizing about how I won around the
company
because you hire people and they come
from Google Apple Microsoft Amazon and
they bring their way with them and what
I realized I was doing was trying to
find some midpoint between how I wanted
to run the company on how they wanted to
run the company which actually made
everyone miserable it's like I had to go
into wartime mode and the crazy thing
was is as I took more command more
control became more decisive more bossy
so to speak
I think people were happier because they
had Clarity and Direction and then the
tide turned or maybe it's like the
Titanic didn't hit the iceberg you go
public Airbnb goes public yes at the end
of 2020. I'm interviewing you live you
can't even speak like you're completely
tongue-tied I actually want you to I
want you to watch it it's such a moment
we just got indication on your opening
price uh shares indicated to open right
now at 139 a share which is more than
double what you priced at I mean are you
at all concerned about froth what do you
think about that number and the
potential that you're leaving billions
of dollars on the table
that's the first time I've heard that
number
um that is that's a
uh you know when we in April
we raised money
um and it was a debt financing oh my God
that price would have priced us around
30 bucks
so I I don't know what else to say it's
that that's a that's a that's a very
that's
um wow
I've watched that in a long time
that actually makes me a little
emotional
what's going through your head in that
moment um
I think that moment it was like my hard
drive crashed and I think it's that like
the pandemic happens we have this
emergency board meeting all of a sudden
I realize like this is going to be a
24-hour thing I probably never stopped
at any point to think of anything you
took a whole year and you made it like a
15 second trailer and I was like oh my
God and it just maybe at that moment it
all hit me
this is just so crazy interview went
viral it did people could see it hit you
yeah yeah yeah my eyebrows went to the
top of my head and um I didn't know they
went that high that was that was one of
the most surprising moments of my life
I'm not usually speechless
I mean 2020 was an intense and emotional
Year and that was the Capstone do you
ever think about where Airbnb would be
if the pandemic didn't happen
that's the crazy thing like
your culture is often forged in your
darkest moments
I think people think of culture as like
you know the perks yoga free food snacks
no culture or the shared behaviors that
you all have based on lessons you've
learned together and the lessons you
remember most are during the moments of
trials and tribulations the things that
Forge you we basically made like five
years of progress in like six months and
you can't ask for an occasion like that
you can only hope that if it happens you
will rise we've seen a lot of founder
CEOs step back whether it's you know
Amazon Google Twitter
Pinterest Slack
you're still here I think when I was
starting out I think I was afraid to run
a giant company but the thing that's
most surprised me is I have more
excitement today
than I did when I was in y combination
the job today as a public company CEO is
more fun really than the job as a
private company I feel like I often hear
the opposite you often do because you
know by the time you run a public
company you're trying to pee
shareholders you're trying to piece
employees you're negotiating I stopped
obsessing over making money and we ended
up generating 300 million free cash flow
there's a paradox there I like to
entrepreneur
think of the growth of your company
you have to grow faster than that and if
you don't grow fast in your company then
your company is going to be pulling you
and then you're going to eventually be
holding it back does it ever feel like
this immense responsibility that you
have to stay or does it feel like a
burden I only want to keep doing this if
I'm the best person to do this and the
interest in these the longer I do it the
more I probably become the best person
because I have both the history the
founder of being a Founder that you can
never replace
and my biggest weakness was probably I
was young and I didn't have a lot of
experience but now I have that too I
think that our day is just getting
started we're like Phase One have an
idea
bring it to Market get product Market
fit phase two hyper growth phase three
become a public company and like
generate Prof and be a real company
phase four reinvent yourself extensively
I'm an entrepreneur and a business
person but I think of myself as kind of
Designing and making and the reason I
like have more fun now is because now
it's more creative than it used to be
are you an artist designer first and CEO
second is that what you would say I
think you're always what you were
growing up you know there's something
about what you are growing up that's
always in your heart and probably I
approach problems more like a designer
than a CEO although I probably set the
interception and how does that change
the company how is that mentality
infused into the company I have like
books like this frankly I'd write book
here right my favorite architect or
Charles and Ray Eames to the great
industrial designers of 20th century
Charles Eames said the details aren't
the details they make the product and I
am absolutely involved in the details I
think design is not just how something
looks it's how it fundamentally works
it's about simplifying something and
people think simplifying is removing
things and it's not simplifying is
understanding something so deeply that
you can get to the essence of something
even like how we became profitable I
like we kind of designed the p l you
know like most people cut we didn't cut
we designed because cutting you're just
like lopping things off but designing
says well instead of cutting all these
expenses what if we just thought about
the whole operation differently to have
fewer Parts fewer components and it
really takes creativity to do that
what's A Day in the Life of Brian chesky
outside the office I like to learn I
like to draw I like to hang out with
people I care about and I like to travel
I guess those are things I do
yeah so this is all this is my life
before Tech did you do these yeah so I
did I did this in uh freshman year RISD
this is like a thousand triangles glued
together to turn into a self-portrait I
didn't realize you were such an artist I
mean I knew you were a designer but I
feel probably yeah more artist out
artist I started as an artist became a
designer then I guess an entrepreneur in
that order
is this another one of yours yeah so
this was like my big high school senior
project this is me basically hanging off
a ledge of the Grand Canyon there's a
lot going on there probably highly
symbolic to how I felt Senior High
School which was like oh my God like my
life is changing so much I was planning
to go to art school I thought to be an
artist I at that point I didn't even
think I'd be a designer designer was
like well leap yeah and I had to go the
whole journey of realizing like I love
drawing
and then I get to campus and I realized
I was born like 100 years too late for
what I wanted to do freshman year is do
you have to pick a major and the
department head of industrial design
came to pitch and they said industrial
design is a sign of everything from a
toothbrush to a spaceship and every
single thing in between and I thought to
myself that's what I'm gonna do with my
life so Airbnb was the thing in between
I guess we're between the toothbrush and
spaceship
[Music]
over the years you really emphasis
Community or connectedness what does it
take to make something that people
really love
when I joined y combinator the first day
they give you a t-shirt it's a great
t-shirt
and it says make something people want
and if you get an exit
they send you a black T-shirt and it
says I made something people want and
that was something that always stuck
with me and I think the way you make
something that people want is you have
to care about people
and you have to understand people we did
this thing 10 years ago I named it Snow
White after the movie Snow White Snow
White was basically the Advent of the
storyboard Walt Disney's one of my
heroes this film was so long he had a
storyboard it and I said why don't more
businesses do that why don't businesses
understand who their customer is
storyboard the experience and then try
to put themselves into shoes that person
in just every single opportunity is a
detail that you could perfect talk about
being in the details oh yeah I mean is
your team like
should we invite Brian or not if they
had the choice that you're presuming
they have a choice
I don't intend to be in the in the
details of everything forever it's like
I'm a coach and I'm like trying to teach
a level of detail and Excellence I think
there's this like idea that I think is a
bit of a myth that great leaders hire
great people and Empower them to do
great work and that sounds great but
they're missing something and what
they're missing is you got to be in the
details of the people it's not
micromanaging it's auditing and
understanding what they're doing Tech is
going through it tumultuous time oh yeah
tens of thousands of people getting laid
off in waves how do you think about how
Amazon and meta and other companies are
handling these layoffs
I always felt like when I would read
some of these corporate Communications
that like they weren't written from by
people they seemed to be like written by
committees and I felt like maybe a bunch
of lawyers HR people had sanded the
edges off the person to the point where
the person speaking wouldn't actually
talk like that any communication I write
a lot of CEOs don't write anything that
they have their name on the second thing
is I think when you do like a layoff if
you're gonna cut you need to cut once
and therefore you better cut deep enough
try to avoid doing multiple layoffs I
think multiple layoffs can be very
difficult from a cultural standpoint
because if there's more than one then
people can't trust they'll ever they'll
ever end and the company is like in a
paralyzed standstill if that happens you
started Airbnb at the depths of the
financial crisis 2009 what's your advice
to entrepreneurs now
I mean I honestly think
hi Sophie
she's like this is going on a really
long time I get it we've been talking a
while
hello
I think she likes me
all right what's your advice look it's
like yeah banks are collapsing like
what's your advice to entrepreneurs
right now
I think this is a great time to start a
company if you look at the history of
companies like apple Microsoft I think
we're starting a down economy Google
emerged during the.com crisis we started
during the Great Recession I like to
tell people the best time to start a
company is the moment you're ready if
your idea is really good and you can
make it in a tough economy you can
definitely make it a good economy and I
think the discipline of being in a
really difficult environment will teach
you something so what do you want the
next phase of Airbnb to be say five
years I feel like at this point we've
all these capabilities it would be such
a shame not to use that to solve a very
important problem and the problem that
I'm most concerned about that I think we
can help is that I think this is the
Loneliest time in human history if
people lived this isolated alone
thousands of years ago before modern
technology would be dead right there's a
reason loneliness hurts it's because
some people would say like Tech is
connecting us all and making us less
lonely loneliness has been rise United
States since 1970s as far as I can tell
so it's definitely not All Tech but I do
think that we need to have a reality
check the average American spends 10
more hours alone every week than 10
years ago we're sleeping less exercising
less spending less time with friends and
family you know your Instagram followers
aren't coming to your funeral no one
changed someone else's Mind YouTube
comment section so we need to marry the
best of the digital technology with the
best of the physical world I went the
next chapter Airbnb I want to be less
about housing less about travel but new
things we're going to do are going to be
a lot more about bringing people
together
[Music]
not bad at all it's so beautiful yeah
Sophie loves to hear I mean look at this
view of the city it's amazing so yeah
here we are Dolores Park
I mean you've been doing this like 15
years yeah 15 years that's a long time
this is a long time does it ever in Tech
standards does it ever get like Lonely
at the Top oh yeah
you can have all the money in the world
all the success in the world but the
thing that makes most people happy is
there's Connections in relationships you
talk about your parents and your family
family like do you want oh yeah
definitely it's probably the one thing I
haven't done I got a dog that was a
starting I'll be kind let me take care
let me take care of something really
like low-key first if you had told me in
my 20s what my life would be like at 41
I would have told you I have a family
and maybe I wouldn't be that far in my
career and now I have like a huge public
company
and I don't have a family and so I did
things in a different order and the last
15 years has been work and all consuming
Airbnb
so what's the goal for the next 10 years
of Brian chesky I think I have to do
things I haven't done before as long as
you're in a constant state of becoming
and changing and growing you're going to
be okay and I think for us like we're in
the tech industry it means we're in the
change industry so we have to change and
reinvent ourselves you obviously you
lived around the world in airbnbs you've
interacted with so many cities and and
people in different countries
many of them welcomed Airbnb with open
arms and some are still resisting yeah
why do you think that is so every city
is a community and every Community has
many different stakeholders and they
have many different circumstances some
cities need more tourism other cities
have been going through a housing
affordability crisis and they're very
very sensitive about housing intake off
the market and so the lesson I've
learned is you gotta like there's no
one-size-fits all you have to treat
every city personally try to make a
system for them that works people think
Airbnb is driving up costs enriching
landlords bringing in floods of tourists
changing the character of a place like
what do you say the people who are like
I I hate what this is doing in my
community well I never want Airbnb to do
anything other than strength in a
community I also think it's really
important to never presume that we're
the good guys is what we're doing like
good for the world and to constantly
reevaluate and so for example affordable
housing a lot of cities said you know we
want to have some basic restrictions on
how everybody can be used in our city so
we have like we comply with registration
systems for cities
we want to make sure that like cities
say they want to be able to that we have
to collect our fair share of taxes but I
also want people to know that we want to
strengthen communities and if that means
that they need to like change the way
Airbnb exists in their City we'll have
that conversation
are you long SF
ultimately I think the cities my God has
it had its fair share of challenges and
I think that I'm saddened that the Tech
Community in the city haven't worked
better together that being said the city
is so resilient yeah and just when
people said there was going to be a
massive Exodus there is a new kind of
probably the word revolution is not an
understatement to say what's going to
happen Ai and a lot of it's happening
right here how do you think AI is going
to change Airbnb I think we can design
some of the best interfaces for AI in
the world and I think what I ultimately
want to do is Imagine One Day the app is
more like a concierge that knows you it
can match you to the perfect airbnbs can
I think that's ultimately what it could
be all right well you know what would
make this world a little more perfect
tell me chocolate chip cookies all right
let's do it Sophie you want cookies all
right exactly what she wants
the key to a good chocolate chip cookie
is lots of brown sugar lots of vanilla
extract that's pretty much all you need
I have a chocolate chip cookie recipe
too so I'm very excited to see what your
secrets are you like baking in general
is this like a thing of yours I do it's
like it's a little like reminds me of
like drawing
drawing is like baking and painting is
like cooking how many chips you put in I
like less chips anymore me too I prefer
more cookie than chip does that seem
good that looks great so now we have
dough all right so ready we're gonna do
like this piece okay
the test is it um
it's pretty good right all right so now
yeah we are
yeah they're kind of
yeah yeah yeah all right
so we're gonna ask a couple real
questions yeah
what's overhyped
crypto was overhyped and now it's not
but crypto was overhyped I think AI is
probably appropriately hyped but there
is a risk that people will have
unrealistic expectations of what it can
do going forward like the whole world
has to move with the technology or the
technology will get ahead of itself so
how much do you really want AI in your
life like would you want chat GPT in
your kitchen there is such a thing as
too much technology in our life
technology is not inevitably a solution
to our problems technology is a tool
it's power and power can make things
better and it can also make things worse
it can simplify our lives or add
complexity it can bring us together or
divide us and the speed at which things
are about to change is something that we
have to be very careful about
10 minutes 10 minutes yeah it's ready
yeah all right let's see what they look
like let's do it
and here they are yum oh my gosh they
look amazing boom there they are look at
that okay shall we let's do it okay
Cheers Cheers
these are 10 star cookies
I was I was skeptical I know I know it's
how can you believe greatness until you
see it you know
[Music]